In this video we'll talk about
在本节视频中
(字幕整理：中国海洋大学 黄海广,haiguang2000@qq.com )
how to get logistic regression to
我们将谈到如何使用逻辑回归 (logistic regression)
work for multi-class classification problems,
来解决多类别分类问题
and in particular I want to
具体来说
tell you about an algorithm called one-versus-all classification.
我想通过一个叫做"一对多" (one-vs-all) 的分类算法
What's a multi-class classification problem?
让你了解什么是多类别分类问题
Here are some examples.
先看这样一些例子
Let's say you want a learning
假如说你现在需要
algorithm to automatically put your
一个学习算法 能自动地
email into different folders or
将邮件归类到不同的文件夹里
to automatically tag your emails.
或者说可以自动地加上标签
So, you might have different folders
那么 你也许需要一些不同的文件夹
or different tags for work email,
或者不同的标签来完成这件事
email from your friends, email
来区分开来自工作的邮件、来自朋友的邮件
from your family and emails about your hobby.
来自家人的邮件或者是有关兴趣爱好的邮件
And so, here, we have
那么
a classification problem with 4
我们就有了
classes, which we might
这样一个分类问题
assign the numbers, the classes
其类别有四个
y1, y2, y3 and
分别用y=1、y=2、y=3、
y4 to, Another
y=4 来代表
example for a medical
另一个例子是有关药物诊断的
diagnosis: if a patient
如果一个病人
comes into your office with
因为鼻塞
maybe a stuffy nose, the possible
来到你的诊所
diagnoses could be that
他可能并没有生病
they're not ill, maybe that's
用 y=1 这个类别来代表
y1; or they have
或者患了感冒 用 y=2 来代表
a cold, 2; or they have the flu.
或者得了流感 y=3
And the third and final example,
第三个例子 也是最后一个例子
if you are using machine learning
如果你正在做有关
to classify the weather, you know,
天气的机器学习分类问题
maybe you want to decide that
那么你可能想要区分
the weather is sunny, cloudy, rainy
哪些天是晴天、多云、雨天、
or snow, or if there's gonna be snow.
或者下雪天
And so, in all of these
对上述所有的例子
examples, Y can take
y 可以取
on a small number of
一个很小的数值
discreet values, maybe 1 to
一个相对"谨慎"的数值
3, 1 to 4 and so on, and
比如1到3、1到4或者其它数值
these are multi-class classification problems.
以上说的都是多类分类问题
And by the way, it doesn't really
顺便一提的是
matter whether we index as
对于下标是 0 1 2 3
0123 or as 1234, I tend
还是 1 2 3 4 都不重要
to index that my classes
我更喜欢将分类
starting from 1 rather than starting from 0.
从 1 开始标而不是 0
But either way, where often, it really doesn't matter.
其实怎样标注都不会影响最后的结果
Whereas previously, for a
然而对于之前的一个
binary classification problem, our data sets look like this.
二元分类问题 我们的数据看起来可能是像这样
For a multi-class classification problem, our
对于一个多类分类问题
data sets may look like
我们的数据集
this, where here, I'm using
或许看起来像这样
three different symbols to represent our three classes.
我用三种不同的符号来代表三个类别
So, the question is: Given the
问题就是
data set with three classes
给出三个类型的数据集
where this is a the
这是一个类别中的样本
example of one class, that's
而这个样本是属于
the example of the different class,
另一个类别
and, that's the example of yet, the third class.
而这个样本属于第三个类别
How do we get a learning algorithm to work for the setting?
我们如何得到一个学习算法来进行分类呢？
We already know how to
我们现在已经知道如何
do binary classification, using logistic
进行二元分类
regression, we know how the,
可以使用逻辑斯特回归
you know, maybe, for the straight line,
对于直线或许你也知道
to separate the positive and negative classes.
可以将数据集一分为二为正类和负类
Using an idea called one
用一对多的
versus all classification, we can
分类思想
then take this, and, make
我们可以
it work for multi-class classification, as well.
将其用在多类分类问题上
Here's how one versus all classification works.
下面将介绍如何进行一对多的分类工作
And, this is also sometimes called "one versus rest."
有时这个方法也被称为"一对余"方法
Let's say, we have a training
现在我们有一个训练集
set, like that shown on the
好比左边表示的
left, where we have 3 classes.
有三个类别
So, if y1, we denote that
我们用三角形表示 y=1
with a triangle if y2 the
方框表示 y=2
square and, if y3 then, the cross.
叉叉表示 y=3
What we're going to do is,
我们下面要做的就是
take a training set, and, turn
使用一个训练集
this into three separate binary classification problems.
将其分成三个二元分类问题
So, I'll turn this into three separate
所以我将它分成三个
two class classification problems.
二元分类问题
So let's start with Class 1, which is a triangle.
我们先从用三角形代表的类别1开始
We are going to essentially create a
实际上我们可以创建一个
new, sort of fake training set.
新的"伪"训练集
where classes 2 and 3
类型2和类型3
get assigned to the negative
定为负类
class and class 1
类型1
gets assigned to the positive class
设定为正类
when we create a new training
我们创建一个新的
set if that's showing
训练集
on the right and we're going
如右侧所示的那样
to fit a classifier, which I'm
我们要拟合出一个合适的分类器
going to call h subscript theta
我们称其为
superscript 1 of x
h 下标 θ 上标(1) (x)
where here, the triangles
这里的三角形是正样本
are the positive examples and the circles are the negative examples.
而圆形代表负样本
So, think of the triangles be
可以这样想
assigned the value of 1
设置三角形的值为1
and the circles the sum, the value of zero.
圆形的值为0
And we're just going to train
下面我们来训练一个标准的
a standard logistic regression crossfire
逻辑回归分类器
and maybe that will give us a position boundary.
这样我们就得到一个正边界
OK?
对吧?
The superscript 1 here is the class one.
这里上标(1)表示类别1
So, we're doing this for the triangle first class.
我们可以像这样对三角形类别这么做
Next, we do the same thing for class 2.
下面 我们将为类别2做同样的工作
Going to take the squares and
取这些方块样本
assign the squares as the
然后将这些方块
positive class and assign
作为正样本
every thing else the triangles and the crosses as the negative class.
设其它的为三角形和叉形类别为负样本
and then we fit a second logistic regression classifier.
这样我们找到第二个合适的逻辑回归分类器
I'm gonna call this H of X
我们称为 h 下标 θ 上标(2) (x)
superscript 2, where the
其中上标(2)表示
superscript 2 denotes that
是类别2
we're now doing this:  treating the
所以我们做的就是
square class as the positive
把方块类当做正样本
class and maybe we get the classifier like that.
我们可能便会得到这样的一个分类器
And finally, we do the
最后 同样地
same thing for the third
我们对第三个类别采用同样的方法
class and fit a third
并找出
classifier H superscript 3
第三个分类器 h 下标 θ 上标(3) (x)
of X and maybe this
或许这么做
will give us a decision boundary
可以给出一个像这样的
or give us a classifier that separates
判别边界
the positive and negative examples like that.
或者说分类器 能这样分开正负样本
So, to summarize, what we've
总而言之
done is we fit 3 classifiers.
我们已经拟合出三个分类器
So, for I equals 1
对于 i 等于1、2、3
2 3 we'll fit a classifier
我们都找到了一个分类器
H superscript I subscript theta
h 上标(i) 下标θ 括号 x
of X, thus trying to
通过这样来尝试
estimate what is the
估计出
probability that y is
给出 x 和先验 θ 时
equal to class I given X and prioritize by theta.
y的值等于 i 的概率
Right?
对么？
So, in the first
在一开始
instance, for this first one
对于第一个在这里的
up here, this classifier
分类器
with learning to by the triangle.
完成了对三角形的识别
So it's thinking of the triangles as a positive class.
把三角形当做是正类别
So, X superscript one is
所以 h(1) 实际上是在计算
essentially trying to estimate what is
给定x 以 θ 为参数时
the probability that the Y
y的值为1的
is equal to one, given
概率是多少
X and parametrized by theta.
And similarly, this is treating,
同样地 这个也是这么处理
you know, the square class as
矩形类型当做一个正类别
a positive took pause so its
同样地
trying to estimate the probability that y2 and so on.
可以计算出 y=2 的概率和其它的概率值来
So we now have 3 classifiers each
现在我们便有了三个分类器
of which was trained is one of the three crosses.
且每个分类器都作为其中一种情况进行训练
Just to summarize, what we've
总之
done is we've, we want
我们已经把要做的做完了
to train a logistic regression
现在要做的就是训练这个
classifier, H superscript I
逻辑回归分类器 h(i)
of X, for each plus
i that predicts it's probably a
其中 i 对应每一个可能的 y=i
y i. Finally, to
最后
make a prediction when we
为了做出预测
give it a new input x and
我们给出输入一个新的 x 值
we want to make a prediction,
用这个做预测
we do is we just
我们要做的
run Let's say three
就是
what run our 3 of our
在我们三个分类器
classifiers on the input
里面输入 x
x and we then
然后
pick the class i that maximizes the three.
我们选择一个让 h 最大的 i
So, we just you know, basically
你现在知道了
pick the classifier, pick whichever
基本的挑选分类器的方法
one of the three classifiers is
选择出哪一个分类器是
most confident, or most enthusistically
可信度最高效果最好的
says that it thinks it has a right class.
那么就可认为得到一个正确的分类
So, whichever value of i
无论i值是多少
gives us the highest probability, we
我们都有最高的概率值
then predict y to be that value.
我们预测 y 就是那个值
So, that's it for multi-class
这就是多类别分类问题
classification and one-versus-all method.
以及一对多的方法
And with this little method
通过这个小方法
you can now take the logistic
你现在也可以将
regression classifier and make
逻辑回归分类器
it work on multi-class classification problems as well.
用在多类分类的问题上